Guide to the Records of the Office of the President (Dr. James McNaughton Hester) RG.3.0.7
New York University Archives
- Series I: Alphabetical, 1961-1969 (Boxes 1-20)
  - U.S. Government, Legislation, Health Professors, Education Assistance of, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - U.S. Government, Legislation, Proposed National Humanities Foundation, 1964-1965 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - U.S. Government, National Science Foundation, 1965-1966 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - University College of Arts and Sciences, 1967-1968 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - University Tax Advisor, 1965-1967 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - University Valley, 1964-1967 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence V, 1966-1969 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Vice President for Acedemic Affairs, 1967-1968 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Vice President for Business Affairs, 1965-1967 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Vice President for Humanities and Social Sciences, 1966-1967 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Vice President for Institutional Facilities, 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Vice President for Scientific Affairs, 1965 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Vice President for Scientific Affairs, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Vice President and Secretary and General Council, 1966-1968 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence WA-WASE, 1965-1968 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence WASH-WAY, 1965-1969 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence WASH-WAY, Washington University Alumni News, 1968 (Box 19)
  - General Correspondence WD-Western, 1967-1969 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence Western-WHN, 1967-1969 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence WI, 1958 1966-1968 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence WN-WY, 1966-1969 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Washington Square, College of, Arts and Sciences, 1965-1966 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Washington Square, College of, Arts and Sciences, 1966-1968 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence Y, 1967-1969 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence ZA-ZE, 1966-1969 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence ZI-ZU, 1966-1969 (Box 20, Folder 6)
- Series II: Administration, 1965-1975 (Boxes 21-24)
  The administration series consists of 20 linear inches of material organized alphabetically by subject. Within each folder the material is organized chronologically. The series relates to general administrative activities and academic matters, including office services, research, libraries, legal matters, university history, the Hall of Fame, the art collection, and program development.
  Box 21 consists primarily of information regarding alumni and announcements and circulars from the President's office. In the original inventory, alumni affairs was a separate series and included all New York University alumni activities, associations, and correspondence with or regarding an individual alumnus. Because this information consisted of only two folders, it has been incorporated into the administration series.
  Box 22 contains materials of considerable interest to researchers. Folders 4-7 include information about the disagreement between President Hester and Parks Commissioner Robert Moses over whether or not the Hall of Fame would be moved after NYU abandoned the Heights campus. Folder 8 contains information about the history of NYU and the Washington Square area in general, including a report on NYU's budget from 1849. Box 22, folder 9 and Box 23, folder 1 contain information about the establishment of the NYU Archives and its early history.
  Box 23, folders 2-11 and Box 4, folder 1-3 contain information about NYU's legal difficulties with professors and students. Folder 11 includes information on NYU professors who protested denial of tenure.
  Box 24, folder 5 contains information about the debate over NYU's purchase of a nuclear reactor and a community protest on the matter. There is also additional information about NYU's participation in the United States Bicentennial celebration. Material on this subject also exists separately in the University Archives (MC 144). The minutes regarding the bicentennial have been removed from this collection and stored with the other material.
  - Academic Matters, 1970-1973 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Academic Matters, Program Development, 1965-1970 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Academic Matters, Program Development, 1971-1974 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Academic Matters, Program Development, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Alumni Affairs, 1973-1974 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Alumni Affairs, 1974-1975 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Alumni Correspondence, 1971-1975 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Announcements and Circular Memos, 1968-1972 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Announcements and Circular Memos, 1973-1975 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Announcements and Circular Memos, Presidents, 1965-1969 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Announcements and Circular Memos, Presidents, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Announcements and Circular Memos, Presidents, 1971-1972 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Announcements and Circular Memos, Presidents, 1973-1975 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Consultants, 1973-1975 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Consultants: Booz, Allen, & Hamilton, Inc., 1973-1974 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Hall of Fame, 1972-1973 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Hall of Fame, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Hall of Fame, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Hall of Fame, 1973-1975 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - History of NYU, 1970-1975 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - History of NYU, Archivist, 1967-1969 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - History of NYU, Archivist, 1970-1973 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Legal, 1971-1975 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Legal Opinions, 1968-1975 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Legal Opinions, Bosch, 1972-1975 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Legal Opinions, Criezis, Electra, 1970-1975 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Legal Opinions, Georgiadis, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Legal Opinions, Georgiadis, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Legal Opinions, Georgiadis, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Legal Opinions, Guarniei, 1970-1973 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Legal Opinions, Munshi and Rosen, 1970-1973 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Legal, 1971-1975 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Legal Opinions, Munshi and Rosen, 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Legal, 1971-1975 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Libraries, 1972-1974 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Libraries, 1974-1975 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Nuclear Reactor, 1969-1970 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Research and Planning, 1968-1974 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Research and Planning, 1975 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Research and Planning Reports, 1974-1975 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Resignation and Work at United Nations University, 1973-1975 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - US Bicentennial, 1971-1973 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - US Bicentennial, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - US Bicentennial, 1975 (Box 24, Folder 11)
- Series III: Associations, 1961-1977 (Boxes 25-37)
  The associations series consists of 65 linear inches of materials arranged alphabetically by name of association. The correspondence, minutes, and publications in this series contains little information about the University. The information pertains to a number of professional educational organizations to which Hester and NYU belonged. It relates to the broader educational world, and only rarely gives insight into NYU. However, the series shows the attitudes of educational administrators during the mid and late 1960s and early 1970s.
  - Associations, A-E, 1970-1975 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Associations, F-I, 1970-1975 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Associations, J-Z, 1970-1975 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Academy for Education Development, 1968-1974 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - American Assoc. for Advancement of Science, 1974-1975 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - American Assoc. for University Professors, 1970-1973 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - American Association of University Women, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - American Council on Education, 1966-1973 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - American Council on Education, 1973-1975 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - ACE: Board of Directors, 1967-1968 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - ACE: Commission on Federal Relations, 1969-1974 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - ACE: Board of Directors, 1969-1973 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - ACE: Wages and Prices, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Association of American Colleges, 1971-1975 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Association of American Colleges: Meetings, 1969-1973 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Assoc. of Amer. Colleges: Comm. on Nominations, 1973-1975 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Association of American Universities(AAU): Committee on Federal Relations, 1968-1973 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - AAU: Council on Federal Relations, 1973-1975 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - AAU: Executive Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - AAU: Executive Committee, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - AAU: Executive Committee, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - AAU: Executive Committee, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - AAU: Executive Committee, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - AAU: Executive Committee, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - AAU: Executive Committee, 1975 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - AAU: Executive Committee, 1975 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - AAU: General Correspondence, 1970-1972 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - AAU: General Correspondence, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - AAU: General Correspondence, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - AAU: General Correspondence, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - AAU: Minutes, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - AAU: Minutes, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - AAU: Minutes, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - AAU: Task Force on Private Higher Education, 1971 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Assoc. of Colleges & Univ. of State of NY, 1965-1974 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - ACUNY, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - ACUNY: Annual Meeting, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - ACUNY: Annual Meeting, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - ACUNY: Commiss. on Indep. Coll. & Univ., 1969-1972 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - ACUNY: " " ", 1972 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - ACUNY: " " ", 1972 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - ACUNY: " " ", 1972-1974 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - ACUNY: " " ", 1973 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - ACUNY: " " ", 1973 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - ACUNY: " " ", 1974 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - ACUNY: Comm. Ind. Coll. & Univ., 1974 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - ACUNY: " " ", 1975 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - ACUNY: " " ", 1975 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - ACUNY: " " ", 1975 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - ACUNY: " " ":Brd.Trustee Form., 1972 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - ACUNY: " " ":Search Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - ACUNY: Executive Committee, 1973-1975 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - ACUNY: Exec.Comm.meeting at Renssilaierville, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - ACUNY: " " ", 1975 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - ACUNY: " " ", 1972 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - ACUNY: " " ", 1974 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - ACUNY: Six University Group, 1967-1974 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Association of Urban Universities, 1965-1968 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Carnegie Commission on Higher Education, 1969-1975 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Center for Inter American Relations, Inc., 1967-1973 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - City University of New York, 1972-1974 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - CUNY: Baruch College, 1972-1974 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Committee for Economic Development, 1970-1974 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - CED: SubCommitte on Mgmt & Financing of Coll., 1971-1973 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Consortium of Univ. in Mid Atlantic States, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Council for Financial Aid to Education, Inc., 1970-1973 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - CFAE, Inc., 1973 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - CFAE, Inc., 1974 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - CFAE, Inc., 1975 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - CFAE, Inc.: Executive Committee, 1973-1975 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - CFAE, Inc.: Minutes, 1973-1974 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Council of Higher Ed. Institutions in NYC, 1969-1974 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Danforth Foundation, 1964-1973 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Downtown Lower Manhattan Association, 1965-1973 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Education Commission of the state, 1966-1974 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - EDUCOM, 1968-1976 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Inter American Institute of Ecology, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - International Association of Universities, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - International Assoc. of Univ. (IAU), 1971-1977 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - IAU: Administrative Board, 1970(?) (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - IAU: Administrative Board, Ghana Meeting, 1971-1972 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - IAU: Administrative Board, Ghana Meeting, 1971-1972 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - IAU: Administrative Board, Paris Meeting, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - IAU: Administrative Board, Lima Meeting, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - IAU: Administrative Board, 1973-1974 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - IAU: Administrative Board, NY Meeting, 1973-1974 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - IAU: Administrative Board, NY Meeting Dinner, 1973-1974 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - IAU: Development Committee, 1970-1972 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - IAU: Development Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - IAU: Development Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - IAU: Fourth General Conference, Japan, 1964-1965 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - IAU: Fifth General Conference, Montreal, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - IAU: Sixth General Conference, Moscow, 1973-1974 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - IAU: Sixth General Conference, Moscow, 1975 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - IAU: Seventh General Conference, US, 1971-1975 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - IAU: Membership Lists, 1973-1974 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Men in Finance, 1970-1971 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Middle Atlantic Consortium on Air Pollution, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Modular Endowment Building Program, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - National Fund for Medical Education, 1961-1975 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - National Institute of Ecology, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - National Scholarship fund for Negro Students, 1962-1970 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - New York Coalition, 1967-1972 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - New York Ocean Science Lab, 1969-1975 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - One Hundred Year Association, 1965-1974 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Second Regional Plan, 1965-1968 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Second Regional Plan, 1969-1973 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - State University of New York, 1972-1973 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Sterling Forest Board of Design, 1963-1968 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - United Fund of Greater NY, Inc., 1968-1975 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - United Nations University, 1973-1974 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - University Corp. for Atmospheric Research, 1969-1974 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Univ. Council on Ed. for Public Responsibility, 1965-1969 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - University Seminar on Higher Education, 1961-1970 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Virgin Islands, College of, 1963-1973 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Whitney M. Young Memorial Foundation, 1973-1975 (Box 37, Folder 11)
- Series IV: Development, 1952-1975 (Boxes 38-41)
  The development series consists of 18 linear inches arranged according to Hester's original numbering system. Development's responsibilities included fundraising efforts for the University either through foundations and wealthy individuals. Boxes 38 and 39 contain correspondence and press releases concerning the 25 million dollar grant from the Ford Foundation. Reports from NYU to Ford were separated into their own collection (RG 15.4). Box 40 contains correspondence with the Rockefeller Foundation, Standard Oil, John B. Snow, and the U.S. Government. Box 41 contains correspondence with Xerox and Alumni.
  - DEV, 1972-1975 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - DEV 1 Fund Raising Campaign, 1973-1975 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - DEV 1-2 Fund Raising Campaign, Leadership Co., 1973-1974 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - DEV 1-3 Dental Campaign, 1973-1974 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - DEV 2 Gifts and Grants, 1972-1974 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - DEV 2-1 Avalon Foundation, 1965-1969 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - DEV 2-1 Citibank, 1968-1975 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - DEV 2-1 Danforth Foundation, 1966-1974 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - DEV 2-1 Exxon, 1969-1976 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - DEV 2-1 Ford Foundation, 1962-1968 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - DEV 2-1 Ford Foundation Grant,Press Releases, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - DEV 2-1 Ford Foundation, 1968-1969 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - DEV 2-1 Ford Foundation, 1970 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - DEV 2-1 Ford Foundation, 1971 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - DEV 2-1 Ford Foundation, 1972 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - DEV 2-1 Ford Foundation, 1973 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - DEV 2-1 Ford Foundation, 1974-1975 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - DEV 2-1 General Electric Foundation, 1969-1974 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - DEV 2-1 General Motors, 1968-1975 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - DEV 2-1 Kitlay, Sol, 1972-1973 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - DEV 2-1 Lehman, Robert, 1953-1973 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - DEV 2-1 Maidman, Irving, 1959-1972 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - DEV 2-1 National Science Foundation, 1967-1970 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - DEV 2-1 National Science Foundation, 1971-1974 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - DEV 2-1 OO-OT, 1973-1975 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - DEV 2-1 PE-PH, 1969-1975 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - DEV 2-1 RE-RH, 1972-1974 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - DEV 2-1 RO-RT, 1969-1975 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - DEV 2-1 RU-RZ, 1971-1975 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - DEV 2-1 Rockefeller Foundation, 1972-1975 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - DEV 2-1 Sloan Foundation, 1952-1975 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - DEV 2-1 Snow, John Ben, 1952-1975 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - DEV 2-1 Standard Oil Company, 1965-1975 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - DEV 2-1 TE-TI, 1971-1975 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - DEV 2-1 Thompson, Virgil, 1969-1975 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - DEV 2-1 Tinker Foundation, 1966-1973 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - DEV 2-1 US Government, 1969-1974 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - DEV 2-1 Xerox Corporation, 1973-1974 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - DEV 2-2 Gifts and Grants, 1973 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - DEV 2-2 Gifts and Grants, 1974 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - DEV 2-2 Gifts and Grants, 1975 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - DEV 3 Alumni Fund, 1973-1975 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - DEV 4 Century Club, 1974-1975 (Box 41, Folder 6)
- Series V: Facilities and Services, 1962-1976 (Boxes 41-44)
  The facilities and services series consists of 17 linear inches arranged according to Hester's original numbering system. This series contains files on many of the University buildings. Materials include correspondence, renovation plans, and attempts at finding funds for new buildings.
  Boxes 42 and 43 contain almost exclusively material about Bobst Library. Researchers will find correspondence with contractors, neighborhood residents, major contributors, and library namesake Elmer H. Bobst, among other materials relating to the library's construction. Box 44 continues files on special services of the library such as food service and security.
  - F & S - Facilities and Services, 1972-1974 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - F 1 Buildings, 1973-1975 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - F 1 Meyers Building, 1965-1972 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - F 1-1 Tisch Building, 1969-1972 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - F 1-1 Bassine Building, 1965-1973 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - F 1-1 Bobst Library, 1962-1965 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - F 1-1 Bobst Library, Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - F 1-1 Bobst Library, Correspondence, 1966 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - F 1-1 Bobst Library, 1967 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - F 1-1 Bobst Library, 1968-1969 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - F 1-1 Bobst Library, 1969-1971 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - F 1-1 Bobst Library, 1972-1975 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - F 1-1-1 Bobst Library 12th Floor, 1970-1974 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - F 1-1-2 Bobst Library Architectural info, 1964-1972 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - F 1-1-3 Bobst Library meetings, 1965 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - F 1-1-4 Bobst Library, Federal Grant, 1965-1967 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - F 1-1-6 Bobst,materials for Library Hearing, 1964-1966 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - F 1-1-7 Bobst, City planning Comm. reports, 1966 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - F 1-1 Brookdale Dental Center, 1968-1975 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - F 1-1-3 Bobst Library meetings, 1971-1973 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - F 1-1 Kevorkian, 1968-1974 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - F 1-1 Chemistry Building, 1969-1970 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - F 1-1 Farkas Building, 1965-1973 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - F 1-1 Main Building, 1970-1973 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - F 1-1 Merrill Hall, 1968-1974 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - F 1-1 Tisch Hall & Gould Plaza, 1972-1974 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - F 1-1 Vanderbilt Hall, 1973-1975 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - F 1-2 Buildings, Proposed, 1973-1974 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - F 1-2-1 Buildings, proposed, German House, 1968-1973 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - F 1-2-2 Buildings, proposed, IFA, 1968-1975 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - F 2 Campus Stores, 1972-1973 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - F 3 Food Services, 1973-1976 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - F 4 Landscaping, 1967 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - F 7 Real Estate, 1972-1974 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - F 7-1 Real Estate Holdings, 1971-1974 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - F 7-2 Real Estate, non-educational, 1973-1974 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - F 7-2-1 Non-Educational Apartments, 1973-1974 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - F 8 Residence Halls, 1972-1974 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - F 9 Security and Protection, 1969-1975 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - F 9-1 Security, Special meeting, 1970 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - F 11 Classroom Space, 1970-1974 (Box 44, Folder 17)
- Series VI: Finances, 1966-1975 (Boxes 45-50)
  The finances series measures 28 linear inches and is arranged alphabetically by subject. It consists of material related to auditing, banking, budgets, financial reporting, investments, and related financial matters.
  There are 6 boxes relating to finances. Box 1 consists of general financial information. The file on banking (folder 1) contains a letter from the bank asking NYU to reduce its outstanding debt as well as correspondence about the voting of proxies over dealings with South Africa. The folders on the budget contain general information except for the folder on the five-year plan, which was formulated to put the University on a sound financial footing. This folder also contains the State approval of the plan. The original inventories contains references to folders on expenses. These expenses were not considered of importance to the collection as a whole and have been disposed of.
  Of primary interest in this collection is the information on financial crises both at NYU and in higher education in general. Box 45 contains clippings regarding the financial crisis at NYU. Box 46 contains information about a Task Force established by President Hester to review NYU's financial condition and make recommendations that would alleviate the crisis. Hester also requested suggestions from the faculty and these suggestions are contained in the file entitled "Faculty Responses to Hester Memo of 1/28/71." Among other things, the University realized that many professors would have to be denied tenure and there was an attempt by the University to establish a faculty placement service. The information on these attempts and on the crisis at institutions of higher learning in general is also in Box 46.
  Box 47 contains considerable correspondence regarding the recommendation that NYU save money by closing the Graduate School of Social Work. Initially the University viewed this as a necessary solution unless sufficient funds were raised to guarantee support for the school. The first folders on this controversy are a response to the recommendation to close. As it became obvious that sufficient funds would be raised, the correspondence changed to congratulations on having found a solution.
  Box 47 also contains the Hurd Commission Report. Hurd was appointed chairman of a State Task Force on the Financing of Higher Education in New York State in November 1971. The file consists of his report, findings and recommendations circulated by Commissioner Nyquist, and comments by Professor Arnold Goren. Also in this file is information on NYU's investments including statements from banks and other managers of the endowment funds, and suggestions from within and outside of the University on how to improve income.